[
    {
        "question": "What US state is the Catalina Island located in?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cave, found in central Kentucky, is the world`s longest cave system?",
        "answer": "Mammoth Cave"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kansas City is built at the confluence of what two rivers?",
        "answer": "Kansas River and Missouri River"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Yukon River flows through which US state?",
        "answer": "Alaska"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Granite State`?",
        "answer": "New Hampshire"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Great Pee Dee River flows into what body of water?",
        "answer": "Atlantic Ocean"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state`s name is derived from the French words for `green mountains`?",
        "answer": "Vermont"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much lower does the Dead Sea get every year?",
        "answer": "One meter"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the last capital of the Roman Empire?",
        "answer": "Constantinople"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest lake in Alaska?",
        "answer": "Iliamna Lake"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the earliest known walled city?",
        "answer": "Jericho"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the oldest city in India?",
        "answer": "Varanasi"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary mountain range in Iran?",
        "answer": "Zagros Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first European settlement in Australia located?",
        "answer": "Port Jackson"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier located?",
        "answer": "Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Angostura bitters are named for a town in what country?",
        "answer": "Venezuela"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Guinea-Bissau?",
        "answer": "Bissau"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which continent would you find the Republic of Guinea-Bissau?",
        "answer": "Africa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bissau is the capital of which West African country?",
        "answer": "Guinea-Bissau"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Republic of Guinea-Bissau is located on which African coast?",
        "answer": "Western coast"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year did the Republic of Guinea-Bissau declare independance from Portugal?",
        "answer": "1973"
    },
    {
        "question": "What country borders the Republic of Guinea-Bissau to the north?",
        "answer": "Senegal"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the Great Lakes does not have a border with Canada?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which French landmark is known for its red windmill?",
        "answer": "Moulin Rouge"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Crossroads of America`?",
        "answer": "Indiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "What hotel was made famous by the movie `Lost in Translation`?",
        "answer": "Park Hyatt Tokyo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What Roman building is known as the `Square Colosseum`?",
        "answer": "Palazzo della Civilt\u00e0 Italiana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has the shortest national anthem by text length?",
        "answer": "Japan"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Faroe Islands were named for the Norse word for what?",
        "answer": "Sheep"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the Porcupine Mountains located?",
        "answer": "Michigan"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the Red Sea get its name from?",
        "answer": "Algae blooms"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest borough of New York City?",
        "answer": "Queens"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two rivers flow through the city Charleston, South Carolina?",
        "answer": "Ashley River and Cooper River"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pamlico Sound is located along the shores of which state?",
        "answer": "North Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "What US city is home to the International UFO Museum and Research Center?",
        "answer": "Roswell"
    },
    {
        "question": "What land mass juts into the northern end of Delaware Bay?",
        "answer": "Cape May"
    },
    {
        "question": "Columbia is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "South Carolina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the `Land of Enchantment`?",
        "answer": "New Mexico"
    },
    {
        "question": "Jefferson City is the capital of which US state?",
        "answer": "Missouri"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which European republic was the first to reach Australia in 1606?",
        "answer": "The Dutch"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the strait located between the Italy and Albania?",
        "answer": "Straits of Otranto"
    },
    {
        "question": "What 3 colors make up the flag of France?",
        "answer": "Red, White and Blue"
    },
    {
        "question": "Marbella is a resort on which SpanIsh coast?",
        "answer": "Costa del Sol"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what city are the famous Tivoli Gardens?",
        "answer": "Copenhagen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the capital of Samoa?",
        "answer": "Apia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tirana is the capital of what country?",
        "answer": "Albania"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Hollywood sign sits atop which mountain range?",
        "answer": "Santa Monica Mountains"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which U.S. city was cream cheese invented?",
        "answer": "New York City"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country borders Sweden only by bridge?",
        "answer": "Denmark"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which countries share Lake Geneva?",
        "answer": "Switzerland and France"
    }
]